Greater Cleveland Area, Ohio 216-255-8892 tye.shay.web@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/tye-webster github.com/tyebean *portfolio(link here* in future)

Tye Webster | Software Developer

About Me

I'm a Full Stack Software Developer. My native language is Javascript(ES6). I particularly enjoy working with the React front-end framework. I've experimented with several different backends, a few of those being Express and Python + Flask. A few of my favorite achievements stemmed from those technologies. As a person who admires aesthetics, I'm actively studying the best way to present data in the most user-focused way possible.

Skills

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python Libraries and Frameworks - React, Node.js, Express.js, Flask Database - MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL Other - RESTful Routing JSON

Software Development Projects

Dec 2021 - PRESENT

Proclaim - A responsive web application.

Developed with HTML, CSS, Javascript, Express, Mongoose, and Passport - Deployed with Heroku.

- Created an application with a mobile-first approach and styled using CSS (Cascading Style Sheets) with flexbox layouts.
- Implemented Google OAuth to ensure safe user login and proper authentication code protocols.
- Utilized a MEN stack (MongoDB, Express, Node.js) to build a full stack application in a 7 day development sprint.
- Implements full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting RESTful API calls.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.

Temp Quest - A responsive browser game.

Developed with HTML, CSS, Javascript - Deployed with Surge.

- Rendered appropriate scenarios for end users using event listeners, complex algorithms, and DOM manipulation within Javascript.
- Developed front end UI components utilizing CSS and JavaScript to create intuitive user experience.
- Created a responsive website using mobile first design for mobile and desktop users in a 4 day development sprint.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote

Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

Software Engineering Immersive

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Cuyahoga Community College | Greater Cleveland Area, Ohio

Associate of Arts Aug 2019 - May 2021

- Digital Studio Basics VC&D1015
- Typography VC&D1200
- Visual Communication and Design VC&D1000

Work Experience

Artist | Strongsville City School District | Strongsville, OH

May 2016 - May 2016

- Mocked up an array of designs.
- Completed a high-quality mural in only three weeks.
- Worked collaboratively with multiple stakeholders on a daily basis.

Driver | Uber | Remote

Aug 2018 - Present

- Accepted contracted work on 149+ separate occasions to deliver product independently and in a timely manner.
- Earned up to 92% accuracy on total drives and 80% (reported) customer satisfaction with each drive.
- Reviewed each job carefully, making sure to follow every step in a detail-oriented and accurate manner, earning \$5000+ in "customer to contractor" gifts.